Guide to the Jascha Heifetz Collection ARS.0046
Archive of Recorded Sound
- 12" Sound Discs, 78 rpm discs
  - Test Pressings, 78 rpm discs
    - Box 8: Gramophone, 78 rpm discs
      - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 64, E minor., 1949 June 8-1949 July 12; 6 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 8, Disc 286-291)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; [Sir Thomas Beecham, conductor]
        Gramophone: 2EA 13947-2, 2EA 13948-1, 2EA 13949-2, 2EA 13950-1, 2EA 13851-4A, 2EA 13952-1
        Recorded on June 8, 10 and July 12, 1949
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 9, op. 47, A major., 1949 June 13; 8 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 8, Disc 292-299)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Benno Moiseiwitsch, piano
        Gramophone: 2EA 13982-2, 2EA 13983-2, 2EA 13984-1, 2EA 13985-1, 2EA 13986-1, 2EA 13987-1, 2EA 13988-1 2EA 13989-1
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Romances, violin, orchestra, op. 40, G major., 1950 June 21; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 8, Disc 300-301)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Philharmonia Orchestra
        Gramophone: 2EA 14825-1, 2EA 14826-2
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Romances, violin, orchestra, op. 50, F major., 1950 June 21; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 8, Disc 302-303)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Philharmonia Orchestra; [Walter Susskind, conductor]
        Gramophone: 2EA 14827-2, 2EA 14828-2
      - Lalo, Edouard, 1823-1892. Symphonie espagnole., 1950 June 2; 6 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 8, Disc 304-309)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz; Philarmonia Orchestra; [Walter Susskind, conductor]
        Gramophone: 2EA 14833-1, 2EA 14834-[?], 2EA 14835-2, 2EA 14836-2, 2EA 14837-1, 2EA 14838-1
      - Walton, William, 1902-1983. Concertos, violin, orchestra., 1950 June 26-27; 6 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 8, Disc 310-315)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Philharmonia Orchestra; [William Walton, conductor]
        Gramophone: 2EA 14847-1, 2EA 14848-2, 2EA 14849-1, 2EA 14850-1A, 2EA 14851-1, 2EA 14852-2
    - Box 9: His Master's Voice/RCA Victor/Gramophone, 78 rpm discs
      - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Sonatas, violin, piano, op. 18, E♭ major. Selections, 4 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 9, Disc 334-337)
        Handwritten in black ink on plain white labels: Strauss sonata, 2 mvmt. pt 1 [disc 334] -- Strauss 2nd movement part 2 [disc 335] -- Strauss sonata 3d move. pt 1 [disc 336] -- Strauss sonata 3 m pt 2 [disc 337]
        RCA Victor: 78970-1, 78971-1, 78972-2, 78973-1
      - Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Tzigane [excerpt], 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 9, Disc 338)
        Handwritten in black ink on plain white label: Tzigane, pt 1, Camden
        RCA Victor: 78975-1
      - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Stimmungsbilder. An einsamer Quelle, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 9, Disc 339)
        Title and performer information handwritten in black ink on plain white label
        RCA Victor: 81354-2
      - Hummel, Johann Nepomuk, 1778-1837. Rondos, piano, op. 11, E♭ major; arr., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 9, Disc 340)
        RCA Victor: 81355-3
      - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Sonatinas, violin, piano, D. 408, G minor, 3 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 9, Disc 341-343)
        Title and performer information handwritten in black and blue ink on plain white label
        RCA Victor: 81356, 81357-3A, 81358-2
      - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Sommernachtstraum. Scherzo, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 9, Disc 353)
        Handwritten in blue ink on plain white label: "With exception of one place the record is good"
        RCA Victor: 87283-5
      - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Schwanengesang (Song cycle). Ständchen; arr., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 9, Disc 354)
        Handwritten in blue ink or pencil on plain white label: No. 2 Schubert-Serenade-Stokowski-Phila. Symphony Orch.
        RCA Victor: 92861-1
    - Box 10: RCA Victor, 78 rpm discs
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 3, op. 12, no. 3, E♭ major, 5 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 10, Disc 355-359)
        Title and performer information handwritten in black ink on plain white labels
        RCA Victor: 98694-2, 98695-2, 98696-2, 98697-1, 98698-2
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 7, op. 30, no. 2, C minor, 7 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 10, Disc 360-366)
        RCA Victor: 98699-2, 99500-2, 99501-1, 99502-2, 99503-2, 99504-1
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 8, op. 30, no. 3, G major, 5 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 10, Disc 367-371)
        Title and performer information handwritten in black or blue ink or pencil on plain white labels
        RCA Victor: 99508-1, 99509-2, 99510-2, 99511-2, 99512-2
      - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 2, op. 100, A major, 5 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 10, Disc 372-376)
        RCA Victor: 99513-2, 99514-1, 99515-1, 99516-1, 99517-1
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Sonatas, violin, piano, K. 378, B♭ major, 4 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 10, Disc 377-380)
        Title and performer information handwritten in pencil or black ink on plain labels
        RCA Victor: 99523-2, 99524-2, 99525-1, 99526-2
      - Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 3, op. 45, C minor, 6 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 10, Disc 381-386)
        RCA Victor: 99527-1, 99528-2, 99529-1, 99530-2, 99531-2, 99532-1
      - Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 2, op. 13, G major, 5 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 10, Disc 387-391)
        Title information handwritten in pencil or black ink on plain white labels
        RCA Victor: 99554-1, 99555-2, 99556-2, 99557-2, 99558-2
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Sonatas, violin, piano, K. 454, B♭ major, 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 10, Disc 392-393)
        Title information handwritten in pencil on plain white labels
        RCA Victor: 99559-1, 99560-1 [1st movement only; remaining discs for 2nd-3rd movements located in Box 11]
    - Box 12: RCA Victor, 78 rpm discs
      Koussevitzky, Serge; Boston Symphony Orchestra; Primrose, William; Feuermann, Emanuel; Rubinstein, Artur
      - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Symphonies, no. 4, op. 98, E minor, 6 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 12, Disc 430-435)
        Title and performer information handwritten in blue pencil on plain white labels
        Performed by Boston Symphony Orchestra; Serge Koussevitzky, conductor
        RCA Victor: 028858-1, 028859-1, 028860-1, 028861-2, 028862-1, 028863-2
      - Cities Service Program Excerpt, 12" vinyl 78 rpm sound disc (Box 12, Disc 436)
        Title in typescript on plain white label
        Handwritten in black ink on label: For Jascha Heifetz with sincere admiration - Good morning, Mr. Kreutzer - Frank & Jack
        RCA Victor: 032688-1
      - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 77, D major, 9 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 12, Disc 437-446)
        Title and performer information handwritten in blue pencil with additional comments in pencil, on plain white labels
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz; Boston Symphony Orchestra; [Serge Koussevitzky, conductor]
        RCA Victor: 035425-2, 035426-3, 035427-2, 035428-1, 035428-2, 035429-2, 035430-3, 035431-2, 035432-1
        Disc 437 is broken and has been placed in Box 1
      - Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953. Peti︠a︡ i volk, 6 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 12, Disc 447-452)
        Title and performer information handwritten in blue pencil, with additional comments in pencil or red pencil, on plain white labels
        Performed by the Boston Symphony Orchestra
        RCA Victor: 035433-3, 035434-3, 035435-3, 035436-2, 035437-2, 035438-2
      - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Concertos, violin, violoncello, orchestra, op. 102, A minor, 8 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 12, Disc 453-460)
        Title information handwritten in black ink or red pencil on plain white labels
        RCA Victor: 045645-1, 045646-4R, 045647-2R, 045648-2, 045649-2, 045650-2, 045651-2, 045652-3
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 563, E♭ major [1 movement only], 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 12, Disc 461-462)
        Title information handwritten in pencil, and additional information in pencil or blue ink, on plain white labels
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; William Primrose, viola; [Emanuel Feuermann, violoncello]
        RCA Victor: 061571-1, 061572-1
      - Dohnányi, Ernő, 1877-1960. Serenade, string trio, op. 10, C major, 5 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 12, Disc 463-468)
        Title and performer information handwritten in pencil on plain white labels
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; William Primrose, viola; Emanuel Feuermann, violoncello
        RCA Victor: 061590-3R, 061591-3R, 061592-2R, 061593-2R, 061594-1
        Disc 468 is broken and has been placed in Box 1; a fragment that has broken from the disc is in a separate envelope, housed within a 10" sleeve and placed near the top of the box
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 563, E♭ major, 8 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 12, Disc 469-476)
        Title and performer information handwritten in pencil and blue ink on plain white labels
        RCA Victor: 061605-3R, 061606-2R, 061607-2, 061608-1, 061609-2, 061610-2, 061611-2, 061612-2
      - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Trios, piano, strings, D. 898, B♭ major, 4 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 12, Disc 477-480)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Artur Rubinstein, piano; Emanuel Feuermann, violoncello
        RCA Victor: 061622-2, 061623-3, 061624-4R, 061625-3
        These four discs contain movements 1 and 2 only; the remainder of the work is on discs in Box 13
    - Box 13: RCA Victor, 78 rpm discs
      Feuermann, Emanuel; Goossens, Eugene; Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra; Musical Art Quartet; Sanromá, Jesús María; Primrose, William; Rubinstein, Artur
      - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Trios, piano, strings, D. 898, B♭ major, 4 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 13, Disc 481-484)
        RCA Victor: 061626-2R, 061627-4, 061628-4, 061629-5
        These four discs contain movements 3 and 4 only; the beginning of the work is on discs in Box 12
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Trios, piano, strings, op. 97, B♭ major, 10 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 13, Disc 485-494)
        Title and performer information handwritten in pencil and ink on plain white labels
        RCA Victor: 061634-1, 061635-1, 061636-2, 061637-3, 061638-1, 061639-3, 061640-2, 061641-3, 061642-2, 061643-3
      - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Trios, piano, strings, D. 898, B♭ major, 8 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 13, Disc 495-502)
        RCA Victor: 061644-2R, 061645-1, 061646-2, 061647-2, 061648-4, 061649-2, 061650-3, 061651-3
      - Walton, William, 1902-1983. Concertos, violin, orchestra, 12 12" vinyl 78 rpm sound discs (Box 13, Disc 503-514)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz; Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra; [Eugene Goossens, conductor]
        RCA Victor: 062500-[2?], 062500-2A, 062501-1, 062501-1A, 062502-3, 062502-3A, 062503-2A, 062503-2R [broken disc], 062504-1, 062504-2A, 062505-1A, 062505-3[A?]
        Disc 510 is broken and has been placed in Box 1
      - Chausson, Ernest, 1855-1899. Concert, 8 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 13, Disc 515-522)
        Title, performer information, and additional comments handwritten in pencil and ink on plain white labels
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Jesús María Sanromá, piano; Musical Art Quartet
        RCA Victor: 065377-1A, 065378-1A, 065379-2A, 065380-2, 065381-1A, 065384-1, 065387-2A, 065391-1
      - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Suites, harpsichord, HWV 432, G minor. Passacaille; arr., 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 13, Disc 523-524)
        Title and performer information handwritten in ink on plain white labels; title listed as “ Passacaglia (Handel - Halvorsen)”
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; William Primrose, viola
        RCA Victor: 065639-2, 065640-4
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Duets, violin, viola, K. 424, B♭ major, 5 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 13, Disc 525-529)
        Title and performer information handwritten in ink on plain white labels
        RCA Victor: 065641-4A, 065642-3, 065643-3A, 065644-1A, 065645-1A
      - Benjamin, Arthur, 1893-1960. Romantic fantasy, Disc 531 has a chip missing that may affect beginning of recording; 6 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 13, Disc 530-535)
        Title and performer information handwritten in pencil on plain white labels as “Benjamin Concerto”
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; William Primrose, viola; [unidentified orchestra]
        RCA Victor: 072474-2, 072474-3, 072475-2, 072476-2, 072477-2, 072478-2
    - Box 14: RCA Victor/Victor, 78 rpm discs
      San Francisco Symphony Orchestra; Monteux, Pierre; NBC Symphony Orchestra; Toscanini, Arturo; Voorhees, Donald; Bell Telephone Hour Orchestra; Waxman, Franz, 1906-1967; Achron, Isidor; Pasternack, Josef; RCA Victor Chamber Orchestra; Benoist, André; Chotzinoff, Samuel
      - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonaten und Partiten, violin, BWV 1001-1006. Partita, no. 2. Chaconne, 3 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 14, Disc 536-538)
        Title and additional information handwritten in ink and pencil on plain white labels
        RCA Victor: 072596-2, 072597-1, 072598-2
      - Achron, Joseph, 1886-1943. Hebrew melody., 1917 December 19; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 539)
        Title, performer, and additional information etched into disc
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; [unidentified orchestra]; Josef Pasternack, conductor
        Victor: C-21268-1
      - Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908. Danzas españolas, op. 21. Malagueña., 1917 December 19; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 540)
        Title, performer, and additional information etched into disc. Title etched in disc: Spanische Tänze; written on sleeve: Spanish Dance Malagueña
        Victor: C-21270-3
      - Bazzini, Antonio, 1818-1897. Ronde des lutins., 1917 December 19; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 541)
        Title, performer, and additional information etched into disc. Title etched in disc: La Ronde; written on sleeve: Danse [Dance] of Goblins
        Victor: C-21271-2
      - Wieniawski, Henri, 1835-1880. Concertos, violin, orchestra, no. 2, op. 22, D minor. Romance; arr., 1918 October 3; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 542)
        Title, performer, and additional information etched into disc. Title etched in disc: Romance; written on label and sleeve: Wieniawsky
        Victor: C-22266-1
      - Paganini, Nicolò, 1782-1840. Moto perpetuo; arr., 1918 October 3; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 543)
        Victor: C-22267-2; 74581 (etched in disc)
      - Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908. Introduction et tarantelle, violin, piano, op. 43., 1918 October 3; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 544)
        Victor: C-22268-1
      - Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Nocturnes, piano, op. 9. No. 2; arr., 1918 October 4; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 545)
        Victor: C-22269-4
      - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge, op. 34. Auf Flügeln des Gesanges; arr., 1918 October 4; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 546)
        Title, performer, and additional information etched into disc. Title etched in disc and written on sleeve: On Wings of Song
        Victor: C-22272-2; 74583
      - Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908. Zigeunerweisen., 1919 October 13; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 547)
        Title, performer, and additional information etched into disc. Title etched in disc: Gypsy Airs no. 2
        Victor: C-23407-[1]
      - Lalo, Edouard, 1823-1892. Symphonie espagnole. Andante., 1919 October 14; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 548)
        Victor: C-23408-2
      - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Serenade, string orchestra, op. 48, C major. Valse., 1919 October 14; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 549)
        Victor: C-23409-3
      - Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908. Zigeunerweisen., 1919 October 14; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 550)
        Title, performer, and additional information etched into disc. Title etched in disc: Gypsy Airs no. 1
        Victor: C-23410-2
      - Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Slovanské tance, op. 72. No. 2; arr., 1919 October 14; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 551)
        Title, performer, and additional information etched into disc. Title etched in disc: Slavonic Dance no. 2
        Victor: C-23412-2
      - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Evgeniĭ Onegin. Kuda, vy udalilisʹ., 1922 October 19; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 552)
        Title, performer, and additional information etched into disc. Title etched in disc: Air de Lensky
        Victor: C-27036-2
      - Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908. Danzas españolas, op. 21. Habanera., 1924 December 18; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 553)
        Victor: C-27046-3
      - Achron, Joseph, 1886-1943. Hebrew pieces. Hebrew dance., 1924 September 24; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 554)
        Victor: C-30931-2; 6491A
      - Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 3, op. 45, C minor. Allegretto espressivo alla romanza., 1924 December 18; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 555)
        Title, performer, and additional information etched into disc; title written on label and sleeve in pencil
        Victor: C-31380-2
      - Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Havanaise., 1924 December 19; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 556)
        Victor: C-31382-3
      - Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908. Carmen fantaisie., 1924 December 19; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 557)
        Title, performer, and additional information etched into disc. Title etched in disc: Carmen; written on sleeve: Sarasate
        Victor: C-31383-2
      - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge, op. 34. Auf Flügeln des Gesanges; arr., 1928 May 8; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 558)
        Title, performer, and additional information etched into disc. Title etched in disc: Auf Flugeln; written on sleeve: On Wings of Song
        Victor: CVE-22272-4
      - Achron, Joseph, 1886-1943. Hebrew melody; arr., 1926 December 31; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 559)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; [Isidor Achron, piano]
        Victor: CVE-27034-2
      - Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 3, op. 45, C minor. Allegretto espressivo alla romanza., 1928 May 8; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 560)
        Victor: CVE-31380-4
      - Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Plus que lente; arr., 1925 December 29; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 561)
        Title, performer, and additional information etched into disc. Title etched in disc: La plus que lente; composer written on label and sleeve
        Victor: CVE-34070-4; 6564A-4 (stamped in disc)
      - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonaten und Partiten, violin, BWV 1001-1006. Partita, no. 3. Menuett, no. 1; arr. -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonaten und Partiten, violin, BWV 1001-1006. Partita, no. 3. Menuett, no. 2; arr. -- Couperin, François, 1668-1733. Pièces de clavecin, 3e livre. No 17. Petits moulins à vent; arr., 1925 December 29; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 562)
        Titles, performer, and additional information etched into disc. Titles etched in disc: Minuetto nos. 1 & 2, Les petits moulins
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; [Isidor Achron, piano?]
        Victor: CVE-34072-3; 6564B-3 (stamped in disc)
      - Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946. Canciones populares españolas. Jota; arr. -- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Lyriske stykker, op. 71. Småtrold; arr., 1928 May 8; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 563)
        Titles, performer, and additional information etched into disc. Titles etched in disc: Jota, Puck
        Victor: CVE-43960-2
      - Drake, Milton, 1912-2006; Hoffman, Al, 1902-1960; Livingston, Jerry, 1909-1987. Mairzy doats; arr., [194-?]; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 14, Disc 564)
        Title, performer, and additional information in typescript on label. From label: “For the private collection of: Jascha Heifetz [name handwritten in ink]; Compliments of N.W. Ayer & Son, Inc.”
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Bell Telephone [Hour] Orchestra; Donald Voorhees, conductor
        RCA Victor: AND4-MC-5356-1 (stamped in disc)
      - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 64, E minor., 1944 April 9; 6 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 14, Disc 565-570)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; NBC Symphony Orchestra; Arturo Toscanini, conductor
        RCA Victor: A D4-RC-137-1A [matrix etched in disc], A D4-RC-138-1A, D4-RC-139 [printed on label], A D4-RC-140-1A, A D4-RC-141-1A, A D4-RC-142-1A
        From broadcast April 9, 1944
      - Chausson, Ernest, 1855-1899. Poème, violin, orchestra., 1946 January 23, 1946 January 31; 3 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 14, Disc 571-573)
        Disc 573 is broken and has been placed in Box 1
        Title, performer, and additional information handwritten on label in pencil and ink. Disc 571: 1-31-46 [handwritten in ink on reverse label]; disc 572: Jan 24 1946 [stamped on front label], 1-23-46 [handwritten in ink on reverse label]
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; [San Francisco Symphony Orchestra?]
        RCA Victor: D5-RC-1152-1A, D5-RC-1153-2, D5-RC-1154-2 [broken disc]
      - Gruenberg, Louis, 1884-1964. Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 47., [1945-1946?]; 8 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 14, Disc 574-581)
        Matrix numbers and additional information handwritten in pencil on disc labels. Disc 574: Gruenberg Concerto I [handwritten in ink]; disc 576: 1-22-46 [handwritten in ink on reverse label]; disc 577: Gruenberg Concerto IV [handwritten in ink]; disc 578: 2-7-46 [handwritten in ink on reverse label]; disc 579: Mar 7 1946 [stamped on front label], 3-5-46 [handwritten in ink on reverse label]; disc 580: 2-15-46 [handwritten in ink on reverse label]; disc 581: Mar 7 1946 [stamped on front label], 3-5-46 [handwritten in ink on reverse label]
        Discs 574 and 577 are red vinyl; discs 575, 576, and 578-581 are shellac
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; [San Francisco Symphony Orchestra; Pierre Monteux, conductor?]
        RCA Victor: D-5-RC-1155-1AR, D5-RC-1156-1, D5-RC-1157-2, D-5-RC-1158-1AR, D5-RC-1159-2A, D5-RC-1160-2, D5-RC-1161-2A, D5-RC-1162-2
      - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Concertos, violins (2), string orchestra, BWV 1043, D minor., [1946 October 14, 1946 October 19]; 4 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 14, Disc 582-585)
        Title, performer, and additional information handwritten in pencil and ink on label
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin [Heifetz plays both solo parts]; RCA Victor Chamber Orchestra; [Franz Waxman, conductor]
        RCA Victor: D6-RC-5630-1, D6-RC-5631-2, D6-RC-5632-1, D6-RC-5633-1A
        [Recorded October 14 and 19, 1946]
    - Box 11: RCA Victor, 78 rpm discs
      NBC Symphony Orchestra; Koussevitzky, Serge; Boston Symphony Orchestra
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Sonatas, violin, piano, K. 454, B♭ major, 4 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 11, Disc 394-397)